<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Drewskiwooskie Blogarooskie</title>
    <link>http://drewstud.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Drewskiwooskie Blogarooskie</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 07:35:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://drewstud.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Pianobar Updates On Touchbar With MTMR</title>
      <link>http://drewstud.com/posts/2019-07-12-2019-mtmr-with-pianobar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 07:35:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewstud.com/posts/2019-07-12-2019-mtmr-with-pianobar/</guid>
      <description>I found MTMR and am really liking it so far. However I also enjoy listening to music with Pianobar but saw there was no love to make the current song playing show in the touchbar. The following is what I did to make it work. Mac OSX 10.14.5 is what I am using, but this can also be made to work on any *nix distro as well.
My repo of files are located here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZFS kmod Does Not Build On Fedora Kernel 4.20.4-200</title>
      <link>http://drewstud.com/posts/2019-01-29-2019-zfs-kernel-patch-fedora-kernel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 07:35:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewstud.com/posts/2019-01-29-2019-zfs-kernel-patch-fedora-kernel/</guid>
      <description>After updating my Fedora box, I noticed that the ZFS kernel module was no longer loaded. The error (from /var/lib/dkms/zfs/0.7.12/build/make.log) was:
{% highlight bash %} /var/lib/dkms/zfs/0.7.12/build/include/zpios-ctl.h:186:11: error: implicit declaration of function ‘current_kernel_time’; did you mean ‘current_kernel_time64’? [-Werror=implicit-function-declaration]
ts_now = current_kernel_time();
^~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
current_kernel_time64
/var/lib/dkms/zfs/0.7.12/build/include/zpios-ctl.h:186:9: error: incompatible types when assigning to type ‘struct timespec’ from type ‘int’
ts_now = current_kernel_time();
{% endhighlight %}
The easiest fix is to:
Download zfs-linux_0.6.5.11-1ubuntu3.6.debian.tar.xz  extract and get debian/patches/3204-Add-4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streaming Audio from Linux to OSX with Pulseaudio</title>
      <link>http://drewstud.com/posts/2019-01-02-stream-audio-linux-to-osx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 07:35:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewstud.com/posts/2019-01-02-stream-audio-linux-to-osx/</guid>
      <description>This is not for everyone, and I know that there are better things I can do (like hook up a pair of speakers). Let me explain.
I have a Fedora box that I use as a home personal server. It runs various services. However because the more monitors the better, and I believe in having as many HUDS and graphs as humanly possible, it IS running X and has a monitor attached to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up AWS API Gateway using Chalice, SQS and Celery</title>
      <link>http://drewstud.com/posts/2018-01-31-aws-api-lambda-sqs-celery/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 05:35:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewstud.com/posts/2018-01-31-aws-api-lambda-sqs-celery/</guid>
      <description>End Goal To have an api that sends SQS messages to a queue to be processed by workers.
Flow api request -&amp;gt; AWS API Gateaway -&amp;gt; SQS -&amp;gt; Celery
Why? Why manage an api for yourself when chalice and AWS can handle it quite easily for you. Yes the cloud is someone else&amp;rsquo;s computer, but I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be woken up because a server is down. I would rather be notified because a behemouth like Amazon is down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing OpenBSD On Rackspace Public Cloud</title>
      <link>http://drewstud.com/posts/2016-09-01-openbsd-on-rackspace-public-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 05:35:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewstud.com/posts/2016-09-01-openbsd-on-rackspace-public-cloud/</guid>
      <description>For the longest time I wanted to see OpenBSD on Rackspace Public Cloud. With their boot.iso you are able to attempt to boot into a pxe environment and boot OpenBSD 5.7, but it lacks the necessary drivers for xen. I gave up for a while. but tried with the release of OpenBSD 6. I am happy to report, that you CAN and it WORKS! To do so, you boot into a linux distro, download bsd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Querying Chef REST Api With pure Ruby</title>
      <link>http://drewstud.com/posts/2016-01-19-query-chef-rest-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 05:35:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewstud.com/posts/2016-01-19-query-chef-rest-api/</guid>
      <description>If you want to talk to the chef API without using some wrapper like Ridley, knife, etc.., this is how you do it:
Note: This is taken from here but modified to use httparty {% highlight ruby %} require &amp;lsquo;base64&amp;rsquo; require &amp;lsquo;time&amp;rsquo; require &amp;lsquo;digest/sha1&amp;rsquo; require &amp;lsquo;openssl&amp;rsquo; require &amp;lsquo;net/https&amp;rsquo; require &amp;lsquo;json&amp;rsquo; require &amp;lsquo;pry&amp;rsquo; require &amp;lsquo;httparty&amp;rsquo;
class ChefAPI # Public: Gets/Sets the String path for the HTTP request. attr_accessor :path
# Public: Gets/Sets the String client_name containing the Chef client name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active Directory Password Export Service Silent Install</title>
      <link>http://drewstud.com/posts/2015-10-19-password-export-service-silent-install/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 08:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewstud.com/posts/2015-10-19-password-export-service-silent-install/</guid>
      <description>Password Export Service allows you to export users and passwords from one active directory domain to another. All the guides I found show how to install it graphically. It took a bit but eventually I was able to install the service AND import the key created with ADMT all automatically. I used chef but any automation tool will work. It did require some hacking.
You have to edit the password export service yourself via orca, instEd, etc&amp;hellip; Something has to alter a datbase table, or else it will ALWAYS prompt and ask if you who you want to run the service as.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mailonacircle: Mailinabox(ish) for Centos 7 With Selinux=Enabled</title>
      <link>http://drewstud.com/posts/2015-11-03-centos-mailonacircle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 08:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewstud.com/posts/2015-11-03-centos-mailonacircle/</guid>
      <description>Recently I saw the latest mailinabox, and man is it fancy. I looked, and there was nothing like that for centos. I wanted a way to help the lazy people out there setup a centos 7 box with postfixadmin, dovecot, spamasassin, clamav-milter, postgrey-milter, mariadb, and dkim with ease. So in very short time in between down time, I wrote mailonacircle. It uses chef-solo, and the attributes are basic and do not make a lot of sense at first glance, but it is a start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Centos 7 and systemd-nspawn</title>
      <link>http://drewstud.com/posts/2015-04-18-systemd-nspawn-centos-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2015 08:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewstud.com/posts/2015-04-18-systemd-nspawn-centos-7/</guid>
      <description>With systemd, comes systemd-nspawn. (I will not talk about love/hate of systemd, not in this post at least. Let&amp;rsquo;s just say if you start out saying you are writing an init system, why does your init system takeover acpi?). Anyway, part of the systemd monstrosity is something called nspawn. In short, its a &amp;ldquo;more powerful&amp;rdquo; chroot, but still should not be relied upon soley for security (think defense in depth people!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FreeBSD on Xhyve</title>
      <link>http://drewstud.com/posts/2015-09-04-xhyve-freebsd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2015 08:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewstud.com/posts/2015-09-04-xhyve-freebsd/</guid>
      <description>xhyve is essentially a port of FreeBSD&amp;rsquo;s bhyve to OSX. The instructions show how to run Ubuntu (which you can dissect and figure out how to boot other linux distro&amp;rsquo;s), but lack any documentation on how to run FreeBSD with it. Here is how to do it: Clone and build the latest xhyve {% highlight bash %} git clone git@github.com:mist64/xhyve.git cd hyve make mkdir freebsd cd freebsd {% endhighlight %}  Download latest FreeBSD virtual machine image {% highlight bash %} wget http://ftp10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running postfix 3.0</title>
      <link>http://drewstud.com/posts/2015-02-13-running-postfix-3.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 07:35:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewstud.com/posts/2015-02-13-running-postfix-3.0/</guid>
      <description>Postfix 3.0 stable was released a few days ago (Feb 8). I run a few personal mailservers and decided it would be good if I were to upgrade the one running on Fedora21 (postfix + mysql + spamass-milter + greylisting), This would be a deviation as I would be compling it from source, and who knows what would break with 3.0! Here is a very brief update to what I did to get it working on Fedora 21: {% highlight bash %} yum remove postfix -y wget ftp://postfix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuning Spamassassin</title>
      <link>http://drewstud.com/posts/2015-02-26-tuning-spamassassin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 07:35:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewstud.com/posts/2015-02-26-tuning-spamassassin/</guid>
      <description>For those of us who are not large companies where paying another company for spam protection is an option, combatting spam can be something both fun, and annoying. Hopefully, for any newbies, here are some things to do that can greatly reduce the amount of spam you receive, as well as minimize the amount of false positives of mail identified as spam.
 Have spamassassin learn ham and spam  Many people I have seen just install spamassassin, run sa-update, then complain that they are getting a ton of spam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Figuring this jekyll thing out!</title>
      <link>http://drewstud.com/posts/2015-02-12-figuring-this-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 10:35:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewstud.com/posts/2015-02-12-figuring-this-out/</guid>
      <description>I have read many places that having a blog is a good thing. Even if you have on there something that you think anyone should know, there may be that one person out there who doesn&amp;rsquo;t know, who somehow finds your blog, and you help them. Anyway, this will be a technical blog. I am self taught (no collge) so I am sure there will be lots of people correcting me, which is good, because then I will learn :) Yes this blog is using Jekyll.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://drewstud.com/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewstud.com/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>